The lineage of our grandfather Samuel Bevins is a good place to begin investigating our family
history. Firstly, there is the fact that we have inherited his surname, something we have heard,
spoken, read, or written nearly every day of our lives. So naturally, the etymology of the ‘Bevins’
surname is a subject of personal interest to explore.

But also, our grandfather’s lineage is the most recent of our ancestors to arrive in America. Our
2nd great grandparents, William Longford Bevins and Mary Bolt, and their young son William
Alfred (our 1st great grandparent), immigrated from England in 1845. This simplifies the number
of pathways to explore when determining our immigrant ancestors and their origins and
reconstructing their life stories and historical influences. (1)

Footnote 1: To date, Samuel Bevins and his direct ancestors comprise 43 of the 287 ancestors I
have been able to document. By comparison, his wife, our grandmother Hattie Jane Collins, has
122 known ancestors. Grandfather Ralph Vernon Heddens has 39 (with many more to be
explored), and grandmother Margaret Eva Nattrass has documented 81 ancestors.